Guide to the Barbara Carrasco Papers
Department of Special Collections
Barbara Carrasco papers
ca. 1971-1997
M0880
Carrasco, Barbara
13.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Correspondence, particularly with Harry Gamboa, Jr., Gloria Molina, Edward James Olmos, Cesar Chavez, Dolores Huerta, and Robert Rodriguez, original artwork, material about Cesar Chavez and the UFW, publications about Mexican American art and her own work including issues of Chismearte, Coraz?n de Aztl?n, Americas 2001, Caminos, and La Raza Magazine, photographs and videos.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1996
Biography / Administrative History
Barbara Carrasco is a painter and muralist in Los Angeles whose work has been important in the development of Chicano art, U.S. contemporary political and public art, and women's cultural production. Her art has been collected in the Library of Congress and the Smithsonian Institution.
Between 1976 and 1991, Carrasco worked closely with Cesar Chavez and the United Farm Workers (UFW), producing graphic arts, banners, and murals that were an integral part of the union's activities.
In the early 1980's, Carrasco was at the center of an intense battle over artistics censorship with the Community Redevelopment Agency of the City of Los Angeles, which refused to exhibit her portable mural "L.A. History -- A Mexican Perspective".
Carrasco's other murals include the centerpiece for Luis Valdez's play, Zoot Suit (1978), and a computer animation "mural" on pesticides displayed on the big screen monitor in Times Square.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains correspondence, particularly with Harry Gamboa, Jr., Gloria Molina, Edward James Olmos, Cesar Chavez, Dolores Huerta, and Robert Rodrigue; original artwork; material about Cesar Chavez and the UFW; publications about Mexican American art and her own work including issues of Chismearte, Corazon de Aztlan, Americas 2001, Caminos, and La Raza Magazine, photographs and videos.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Chavez, Cesar, 1927-; Gamboa, Harry.; Huerta, Dolores, 1930-; Molina, Gloria.; Olmos, Edward James.; United Farm Workers.; Mexican American Art; Mexican Americans; Photoprints; Video recordings; Hispanic American women; Chismearte; Corazaon de Aztlaan; Americas 2001; Caminos; La Raza Magazine
Container List
- Correspondence, Series 1
  Includes letters from artists, politicians, and political activitists. Prominent correspondents represented in this series include Gloria Molina, Edward James Olmos, and Harry Gamboa, Jr.
  - General, Subseries a
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Acuna, Rudy (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Aguilar, Laura (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alicia, Juana (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alveranga, Donna (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Atkinson, Karen (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Avila, Glenna (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - B (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Barraza, Santa (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Barrera, Maria (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Becerra, Victor (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bell, Ann (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Brecher, Ken (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Buriaga, Jose Antonio (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Castro, Victoria (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Cervantez, Yreina (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Chacon, Mona (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Cyclona, Robert (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Cyr, Sharon (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - D (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Darder, Antonia (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Davis, Katarina (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - De La Riva, Lola (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Delgado, Roberto (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - E (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Easton, Jennifer (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Eberhard, Lynn (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Enrique, Veronica (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Estrada, William (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - F (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Friis-Hansen, Dana (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Fuglie, Gordon (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - G (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Gallegos, Margaret (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Gamboa, Diane (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Gamboa, Harry Jr.1983 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Gamboa, Harry Jr.1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Gamboa, Harry Jr.1985 - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Gamboa, Harry Jr.n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Gamboa, Manazar (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Goldman, Shifra (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Gonzalez, Jose (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - H (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Hansen, Bob (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Haugh Navarez, Mary Lou (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Healy, Wayne (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Heredia, Lionel (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Huerta-Williamson, Rosa (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Isolde, Ann (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - J (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Jewel Comanies, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Dividend checks
    - K (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Kosiba-Vargas, Apolina (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - L (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Lillys, William (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Lizzarga, David (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Llanes, Llilian (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - M (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Maberry, Sue (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - McCullough, Judith (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Montoya, Richard (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Murakami, Cheryl and Stephen (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - N (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Nava, Robert (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - O (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Olmos, Edward James (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - P (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Patlan, R. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Pintoff, Ernie (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Polakoff, Erica (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Poole, Jean Bruce (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Q (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - R (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Ramona High School (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Rascon, Armando (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Rico, Julie (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Rivera, Gregorio (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Rodriguez, Olivia (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - S (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Sanchez, Marcos (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Sealy, Judith (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Sherburn, Earl (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Tanner, Susan Franklin (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Tafoya, Robert (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Torres, Magdalena (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Towgood, Jean (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - UC Benefits (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - V (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Venegas, Sybil (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Venice Family Clinic (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Viramontes, Helena (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - W (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Weinstock, Steve (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Women's Building (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Woodruff, Judith (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Y (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Yeakey, Lamont (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Zamora, Adolfo (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Ziff, Trisha (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Zimmerman, Don (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified - Marisela (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified - Raquel (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - To people other than Barbara Carrasco (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Outgoing to Dana (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Outgoing to Joe and Blanca (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous unsent postcards (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Get Well Cards, Subseries b
    - A - K (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - L - Z (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Unidentified (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Professional, Subseries c
    - A - E (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - F - N (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - O - R (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Rodriguez, Luis (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - S - Y (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Self-Help Graphics (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - The Women's Building (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Exhibition materials of works by Carrasco, Series 2
  Contains preliminary artwork, camera-ready drawings for community group publications, posters, press releases, photographs, videotape, and clippings relating to public exhibitions of Carrasco's artwork.
  - Scrapbook (Box 4, Folder 6)
    "Barbara's Brag Book"
  - Biographical materials (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Announcements and programs #1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Announcements and programs #2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Announcements and programs #3 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Announcements and programs #4 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Announcements and programs #5 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous publications #1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous publications #2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Art Scene Monthly Guide (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Children Are The Future - Article by Barbara Carrasco (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sign Of The Times - Article by Barbara Carrasco (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Politics Of Art In The Eighties (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Review of L.A. Festival (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Business cards (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Awards (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Exhibition materials of works by others, Series 3
  Contains exhibition invitations and flyers relating to public exhibition of other artist's works. Includes original sketches by Gronk, John Valdez, and Richard Duardo.
  - Announcements and programs #1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Announcements and programs #2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Announcements and programs #3 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Announcements and programs #4 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Announcements and programs #5 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Announcements and programs #6 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Alienz (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Almaraz, Carlos (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Alvarez, Gloria Eredina (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cisneros, Natividad (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Enfiadzhyan, Edward (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Franco, Abel (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Gamboa, Harry Jr. #1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Gamboa, Harry Jr. #2 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Gamboa, Harry Jr. - Support materials (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gamboa, Harry Jr. (Ismania) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Gamboa, Harry Jr. (Jetter's Jinx) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Goldman, Shifra (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Grace, S. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Gronk (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Interview includes WIllie Heron
  - Hansen, Svend wiig (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hernandez, Ester (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Honesto, Cyn (Poems and Other Things) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Limon (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Marie, Teena (Star Child) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Ramieri-Hall, Naomi (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Rodriguez, Robert (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rodriguez, Robert (Assault with a Deadly Weapon) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Rodriguez, Robert (I Rode With Pancho Villa) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Rodriguez, Robert (Poems) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Rodriguez, Robert (Sal Si Puedes) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Second draft
  - Rodriguez, Robert (Tales of Aztlan/The Butcher Defense) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Rodriguez, Robert (Tales of Aztlan/Sal Si Puedes C/S) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Salazar, Igancio Jr. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Velazquez, Gerardo (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous artists (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Project Files, Series 4
  Contains papers relating to the CARA exhibition; an interview with Manazar Gamboa; manuscripts for articles written by Carrasco; information on various conferences and symposia in which Carrasco participated; and sketches, notes, and correspondence relating to various murals done by Carrasco.
  - Ariztlan1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Art X Press1989 - 1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Axis (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Barton, Nancy (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Cafe Cultural1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - California State University Arts at Humboldt University1995 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Chicana Art1995 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Chicana Art Symposium1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Chicana Art: Resistance and Affirmation (CARA) #1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Chicana Art: Resistance and Affirmation (CARA) #2 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Chicana Art: Resistance and Affirmation (CARA) #3 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Chicana Art: Resistance and Affirmation (CARA) #4 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Chicana Art: Resistance and Affirmation (CARA) #5 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - The Chicano Codices1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - The Chicano Expressions1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Comite Arte Popular1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Fine Arts Center (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Gamboa, Manazar (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Getty Center1996 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hall, Gordon Castillo1981 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hear Lies/Here Lies Questionnaires1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Heyek, Deni1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Laguna Art Museum1991 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Los Angeles Center For Photographic Studies (LACPS)1991 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Los Angeles Festival #11990 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Los Angeles Festival #21990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Los Angeles Public Library Mural1989 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Movimiento de Arte Popular Latinoamericano (MAPLA)1983 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Pintoff, Ernest (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Public Art Fund #11989 - 1990 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Public Art Fund #2 - New York Times Square1989 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Ralph's Giant Mural Project (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Under Protest1992 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Undiscover 500 Years: Columbus 1492-1992 - A Comic Strip #11992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Undiscover 500 Years: Columbus 1492-1992 - A Comic Strip #21992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Undiscover 500 Years: Columbus 1492-1992 - A Comic Strip #31992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - University of California, Santa Barbara1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - University of Texas Conference1992 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Women's History Project #11992 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Women's History Project #21992 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Women's History Project #31992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Zoot Suit #1 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Zoot Suit #2 - Photographs (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Zoot Suit #3 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous announcements (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Press releases (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Grants (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Loan agreements and receipts (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Letters of recommendation and non-recommendation (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Rosters (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous writing (Box 11, Folder 6)
- United Farm Workers files, Series 5
  Contains correspondence from Cesar Chavez, Dolores Huerta; drawings by various UFW members, including one by Cesar Chavez; photographs of UFW art and banners which were subsequently destroyed; miscellaneous reports and petitions relating to the UFW; and clippings.
  - Arillanes, Suzanna - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Cesar E. Chavez Foundation - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Chavez, Cesar - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Chavez, Helen - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Chavez, Maria Elena - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Cooperrider, Verne - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Garica, Raul - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Haren, M. - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Hershenbaum, Irv - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Matsumoto, Julie - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 16)
    Includes Oscar Mondragon
  - Olivares, Father Luis - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Ortiz, Frank - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Papert, Joan - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Ponce, Pola - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Rodriguez, Arturo - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Ronquillo, David - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Ruiz, Cecilia - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Sandoval, Gema - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Self-Help Graphics - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Sherman, Joceyln - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - U.F.W. Union AFL-CIO, Los Angeles - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Valila, Marchelle - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Unidentified - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Letter from David Ronquillo to Cesar Chavez regarding Barbara Carrasco (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Letter to editor from Barbara Carrasco regarding Dolores Huerta (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Letter from Barbara Carrasco to Cesar Chavez (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Letter from Barbara Carrasco to David (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Letter from Barbara Carrasco to unidentified regarding Cesar Chavez memorial banner (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Marriage, Quincennera, and funeral mass announcements of U.F.W. members (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - First Annual Cesar E. Chavez Legacy Awards Dinner program (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Cesar Chavez Memorial banner (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Cesar Chavez obituary - Newsweek Magazine1993 May 3 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Cesar Chavez obituary - People Magazine1993 May 10 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Cesar Chavez rememberance - Life Magazine1994 Jan. (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Solidarity: 20th Anniversary U.F.W. booklet (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Fast for Life: July 16 - August 21 1998 Delano, CA (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Fast for Life: Commemorative Journal (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Boycott Grapes: For Your Sake...And Ours (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Grape Boycott - Advertisements (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Grape Boycott - Clippings and miscellany (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - U.F.W. Photographs (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - National Farm Worker Ministry Newsletter (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Huerta, Dolores (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - U.F.W. Flyer (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Drawing by Barbara Carrasco. Signature of Cesar Chavez.
  - Food and Justice #1 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Food and Justice #2 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - El Malcriado (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Intolerable risk: Pesticides in our Children's Food (Box 12, Folder 13)
    Transcription of telephone interview
  - Disguised Weapons (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - The Impact of Pesticides Used on California Table Grapes on Farm Workers, Consumers and the Environment (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - ACTA de La Cuarta Convencion Constitucional de La Union de Campesinos de America, AFL-CIO (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - El Teatro Campesino: The First Twenty Years (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Maryknoll (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper clippings - Cesar Chavez's death and funeral (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper clippings - Cesar Chavez and U.F.W. news (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings - Street and school named after Cesar Chavez (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings - Cesar Chavez's support of artwork (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings - Film about Cesar Chavez (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Volunteer application (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Food and Justice budget documents (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - U.F.W. bumper stickers (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - U.F.W. stamps (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Business cards (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - U.F.W. sketch by Cesar Chavez (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous U.F.W.-related pamplets (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous flyers and pamplets (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous flyers and press releases (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous U.F.W.-related material (Box 13, Folder 14)
- CalArts files, Series 6
  Contains letters, memos, and notes regarding the Masters of Fine Arts degree, including letters of support from Dolores Huerta and Peter Sellars regarding graduation controversy and an audiotape of the review committee meeting discussing the controversy. Also contains Carrasco's Master of Fine Arts project file, and an audiotape and photographs of a staged confrontation with Henry Gamboa, Jr. in a classroom.
  - Administrative papers #1 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Administrative papers #2 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Housing office materials (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Film history papers (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Acuna-Hansen, Chris (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Cervantez, Yreina (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Herron, Willie (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Bang! MFA Exhibition (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Cultural Identity: Inclusion/Exclusion and the Art World Mainstream - Panel discussion (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Family Images/Family Tree Project (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - L.A. Festival (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Pico Mural Project (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Up Against the Wall - Article (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Painting on plywood (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous writing and drawings (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous notes and photocopies of photographs (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous articles and papers (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Soviet Union trips files, Series 7
  Contains correspondence, sketches, buttons, and a videotape relating to her trips to the Soviet Union in 1987 and 1989.
  - Applications, itineraries, newsletters, and misc.1985 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Itineraries, articles on Soviet history and culture, and misc.1987 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Autographed notebook1987 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Autographed palette (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Brochures and receipts (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Unwritten postcards (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous papers #1 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous papers #2 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Goodnight, Paul (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Sketch book pages and drawings, n.d. (Othertype 27, Folder 3)
  - Sketch book, n.d. (Othertype 27, Folder 4)
- Nicaragua trip files, Series 8
  Contains letters, photograph, and memorabilia relating to Carrasco's visit to Nicaragua in 1986. Also includes a sketch of Sandinista general.
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Teaching Materials, Series 9
  Contains correspondence, student papers, and administrative materials relating to Carrasco's teaching activities.
  - Student enrollment and sign-up sheets (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Student papers (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Student project (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Notes from students (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Administrative materials (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Mural project (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings from Daily News (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Receipt and photocopies of checks (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Rudy Acuna lawsuit (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Barbara Carrasco database (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - UCSB Schedule of Classes 1992 and CAA Careers Bulletin (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Notes and miscellany (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous articles (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous flyers (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence from Barbara Carrasco (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Interviews, Series 10
  Contains interviews of Carrasco by various individuals.
  - Phillipe's Eatery1990 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Interview by Nancy Carr1990 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Interview by Juanita Chavezn.d. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Interview by Ann Isolden.d. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - KPBSn.d. (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Cultural Organizations and Publications, Series 11
  Contains biographies, business cards, photographs, broadsides, and other materials documenting various Chicano cultural organizations.
  - Art X Press - Artists' biographies (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Cafe Cultural (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Chismearte (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Galeria Ocaso (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - La Gente (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - La Gente - Photographs (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Business card holder (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Chicano business cards (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Graffiti: an Academy Award nominated live action short / Julio Cortazar., 1 broadside (Othertype 27, Folder 5)
  - Roots of greatness: the 1996 Mexican American historical calendar (Othertype 27, Folder 7)
- Publications, Series 12
  Contains books, exhibition catalogs, and magazines featuring Carrasco and/or her artwork, including multiple issues of Chismearte, Corazon de Aztlan, Americas 2001, High Performance, Art X Press, Pro Fun, Framework, Community Murals, and Caminos.
  - Exhibition Catalogues, Subseries a
    - Arte Chicano Carteles (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - El Barrio (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Catch a Rising Star (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - CSU Summer Arts (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Current Art (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - ExhibitsUSA (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - First Annual Hispanic Heritage Art Auction (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Image & Identity (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - LA Hot and Cool (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Latina Art: Showcase '87 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Made in Aztlan (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - MOCA Art Auction ' 94 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Southern California Women's Caucus for Art (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - V Festival Internacional de la Raza (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Books, Subseries b
    - Das Andere Amerika / Philip S. Froner and Reinhard Schultz. -- Berlin: Elefanten Press, 1983. (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Chicano and Latino Artists of Los Angeles / Alejandro Rosas. -- Glendale: CP Graphics, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 1)